Yes, blowing in the wind, I ain't got nothing else to lose
Blowing in the wind
How many years must a man face this
Oh, it is what you have to see
Before they learn to live
How many times must a man pretend
Pretend that he just doesn't see
Blowing in the wind, my friend, it's blowing in the wind
How many years must a man face this
How many times must a man pretend
Pretend that he just doesn't see
Blowing in the wind, my friend, it's blowing in the wind
How many times must a man pretend
Before he can see the sky
How many years must a man live before he can hear
People cry, how many days will it take to live alone
Too many people have died
Blowing in the wind, it's blowing in the wind
Blowing in the wind, my friend, it's blowing in the wind
How many times must a man pretend
Before he can see the sky
How many years must a man pretend
*outro*